Last time on Kaiju No. 8...
《怪獸8號》前情提要
What's going on? What's happening out there?
怎麼回事？發生什麼事了？
We're picking up live signals from the Kaiju they already killed!
原本已經死亡的怪獸，現在又顯現反應了
You did a great job, Kikoru!
琪歌露，你很努力了
Sorry. I'm running out of time here.
抱歉，我沒時間了
So I'm cleaning you up...
就讓我一拳…
with one punch!
把你解體
An unexpected incident occurred,
雖然遭遇突發事件
but Senpai's last exam came to an end.
但前輩最後的測驗也就此結束
And I have you to thank for encouraging me.
這都要多虧你推了我一把
Thanks, Ichikawa.
謝謝你，市川
After all he went through, Senpai looked even more like a man you could count on.
克服困難後的前輩，看起來變得更可靠了
I can't take this!
絕對不可能的
Never mind.
原來是我的錯覺
I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared!
好可怕，好可怕啊…
And it's all your fault!
都是你害的
I'm only suffering like this because you encouraged me!
都是因為你推了我一把 才害我要經歷這些事
You were thanking me for it at the hospital!
你在醫院的時候，明明就很感謝我
You were so cool then! What happened?
那個豁達的前輩跑去哪了？
Kafka! Ichikawa!
卡夫卡、市川
You've both got mail.
有你們的信件
Okay, we open it on three.
好，數到三就打開
No matter how it turns out, this is my last shot.
不管結果如何，這都是最後了
Will the path I'm on take me all the way to her?
我的道路能否通往她的身旁？
Time to find out!
勝負揭曉
One, two...
一、二…
KAFKA HIBINO EXAMINATION RESULTS
（日比野卡夫卡，測驗結果）
EPISODE 5: JOINING UP!
（第5集：入隊！）
Hey.
嘿
Well, I figured you'd pass.
我就知道你會合格
Same to you.
你也是啊
I'm not seeing any big surprises here.
大部分都如我所料
I don't see Shinomiya's groupie, though.
沒看到四之宮的追隨者呢
You wanted him to pass?
你希望他合格嗎？
No, I...
不，我…
Hey, it's Shinomiya!
是四之宮
Shinomiya-san!
四之宮小姐
I heard you were the top scorer!
聽說你是榜首
Yeah, they asked me handle the oath.
嗯，他們要我當宣誓代表
I can't wait to work with you!
-請你多多指教囉 -彼此彼此
Before the test, I was sure I'd be number one.
參加測驗前，我還以為自己會是榜首
But after what we saw...
但看到她的表現之後…
I suppose we'll be competing for the number two slot.
我們要來爭第二名嗎？
I scored the highest on the fitness exam.
體力審查的第一名是我
You can aim for number two.
你就爭取第二名吧
I'll aim for number one.
我的目標是第一名
Oh, sorry!
抱歉
Hey, you were with the old dude!
你…是那個大叔的夥伴，對吧？
Reno Ichikawa.
我是市川雷諾
Sorry, I'm bad with names.
抱歉，我不擅長記名字
I'm Iharu Furuhashi.
我是古橋伊春
A pleasure to meet you, Furuhashi-san.
請多指教，古橋先生
Just call me Iharu, Reno.
叫我伊春就好，雷諾
Okay.
好
Where's the old dude? Didn't work out?
大叔咧？他落榜了嗎？
Senpai is...
前輩他…
Captain Mina Ashiro is entering the room.
有請亞白米娜隊長入場
Captain Ashiro...
亞白隊長
It's finally time!
終於到這時刻了
The induction ceremony will now begin.
現在頒發入隊證書
Kikoru Shinomiya will speak on behalf of the incoming class!
防衛隊合格者代表，四之宮琪歌露
Yes, ma'am!
是
The twenty-seven of you are, as of this moment,
即日起，任命你們27人
officers in the Defense Force!
成為防衛隊員
On behalf of all 27 of us, I swear that we will lay down our lives for the cause!
我謹代表27名隊員 在此宣誓將拼命奮戰
You helped a lot during the incident after the exam.
測驗結束後的事件，你也幫了很大的忙
Thanks to you, there were no casualties.
託你的福，才沒有人遇害
Again, you have my thanks.
讓我再次向你道謝
It wasn't me who defeated it.
打倒怪獸的不是我
Kafka Hibino, you should be the one hearing these words...
日比野卡夫卡，這句感謝應該是屬於你的
So why aren't you here?
為什麼你卻不在場？
You had the audacity to not only save my life,
你竟敢在救了我之後
but to worry about me like I was a little girl...
還自以為是地擔心我的安危
I'm glad you're safe!
幸好你沒事
This is humiliating!
真羞辱人！
I still want some answers from you about that Kaiju form, too!
我還想質問你變成怪獸是怎麼回事
I'm not gonna let you just up and disappear on me!
不准你就此消失在我眼前！
Excuse me!
不好意思
Sorry to interrupt the ceremony!
請恕我中途參加
The old dude!
大叔？
Number 2032. Kafka Hibino.
2032號，日比野卡夫卡
Failed.
不合格
He scored the lowest on the fitness exam
體力審查為最低等級
and a zero on his aptitude test, so there's not much to talk about.
現階段的戰鬥服適應性為零 我想這也無可奈何
Yeah, sounds about right to me.
嗯，我想也是
-I don't—— -All righty, I'll take him, then.
-我沒異… -那我就接收他吧
Sure, his numbers are below average.
他的成績確實低於平均分數
He doesn't have what it takes to be an officer.
以隊員來說，他不合格
But in actual combat during the last exam,
但在最後的實戰測驗中
he was able to locate the enemy's weak points,
他找出了敵方的要害
and he also aided the overall effort
不顧自己的分數，優先援護其他人
by prioritizing helping others over his own kill count.
對討伐有所貢獻
Not many people are capable of that.
這點實屬不易
And more than anything...
更重要的是…
The dude was funny as hell.
他身為搞笑隊員，表現很優秀
Is that really all you care about?
果然這才是重點嗎？
I'm not sure if we'll ever promote him to a full officer,
我不知道他能否升格為正式隊員
but I'll bring him into my platoon as a cadet and give him some more training.
但就讓他當候補隊員 在我的小隊重新接受鍛鍊吧
He's being enrolled as a cadet,
他是以候補隊員身分入隊
so I had him sit out the induction ceremony.
所以我們沒讓他參加入隊儀式
Glad to hear it, Kafka Hibino.
這樣才對嘛，日比野卡夫卡
So I was right. He did pass.
他果然也合格了啊
As a cadet, though.
雖然是候補隊員
That's a surprise.
真讓人跌破眼鏡
All right, now that we're all here, let's have a word from Captain Ashiro.
既然全員到齊了，就請亞白隊長致辭
Everyone, I'm glad that you all decided to volunteer for the Defense Force,
各位，首先對於大家立志加入防衛隊 並撐過嚴格的測驗
enduring and passing that difficult exam.
最後順利合格，我感到很高興
I thank you.
謝謝大家
These last few years,
近年來
we've seen far more Kaiju
怪獸出現的次數和怪獸規模
We've also now seen this strange incident where dead Kaiju came back to life.
還發生了死亡怪獸復活的罕見事件
These neutralization missions will be extremely dangerous.
要冒生命危險執行的討伐工作 想必只會有增無減
Some of you may die on your very first one.
說不定第一個任務就會有人陣亡
There's absolutely no guarantee that you'll survive.
各位的生命安全毫無保障
But even so... No, that's exactly why...
但即使如此，也正因如此
I want you to entrust your lives to me.
我希望各位能把生命交到我手上
I swear to be standing at the very front, acting as both your shield and spear!
我發誓會站在最前線 成為你們的盾牌與長矛
I'll...
我也很快…
I'll be standing next to you soon, Mina!
就會站到你身邊的，米娜！
HUH?
（什麼？）
AWKWARD
（傻眼）
What the hell?!
這傢伙是怎樣？
He's gone crazy!
他瘋了
He's calling Captain Ashiro by her first name!
竟敢直呼亞白隊長的名字
OOPS
（呃…）
Kaf...
卡…
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
You spoke out of turn and disrespected a superior officer.
你擅自發言，還直呼長官名諱
You owe me one hundred push-ups.
罰你做100下伏地挺身
I didn't mean to say that out loud!
我不小心說出口了！
He's already at it!
這麼快就開始搞笑啦
Captain Ashiro, I think you're going a little easy on the guy...
亞白隊長，懲罰會不會有點太輕了？
Huh?
咦？
Did I just see her smile?
她剛才是不是笑了？
He just got here and he's already bringing the comedy?
副隊長，你的搞笑隊員 馬上就發揮作用了呢
I know, right? I told you.
對吧？一切都如我所料
This place can get pretty gloomy sometimes.
畢竟這份工作很沉重
We need a guy like him.
我覺得我們正需要這種人
Well, that's only half the story.
以上有一半是場面話
When those Kaiju started coming back from the dead,
在怪獸陸續復活的時候
we suddenly saw a 9.8 fortitude Kaiju signal.
突然出現怪獸規模9.8的反應
I still think it was just a busted sensor,
雖然我覺得應該是系統誤判
but at the same time, somebody's vitals stopped coming in.
但同時某個人的生命徵象莫名消失了
Kafka Hibino...
日比野卡夫卡
There's something strange about him,
他對戰鬥服的適應性也異常地低
and not just the fact that his suit aptitude was zero.
總覺得這傢伙哪裡不對勁
I'm going to keep him close and find out what that "something" is.
所以我要把他留在身邊 找出不對勁的真相
Ninety-nine...
99…
You really hung in there, old dude!
大叔，辛苦你了
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Come with me. We need to talk.
你過來，我有話跟你說
What, we can't do it here?
幹嘛？不能在這裡說嗎？
But if we did it here...
這裡不太方便
Are you confessing your love?
你該不會是要告白吧？
It is not!
才不是！
Senpai!
前輩
So it's one of those "meet me after school behind the gym" things?
那是要找我去體育館後面單挑嗎？
Just come with me!
你跟我來就對了
You ate a Kaiju and turned into one?
你吃了怪獸就變成怪獸？
I can't believe it!
太扯了吧
God, you're such a glutton.
你胃口還真好啊
I didn't mean to eat it!
你以為我願意吃嗎？
You're both way too loud!
你們兩個太大聲了
I think we could just tell the Defense Force, you know.
我有想過乾脆把這件事告訴防衛隊
They might be able to cure me!
搞不好他們能把我治好
Not a chance.
這不可能
Even if they don't kill you outright,
就算你能逃過撲殺處分
you'll spend every day being tested and doing experiments.
也得天天接受檢查和實驗
You'll never be a defense officer.
你也沒辦法成為防衛隊員了
Really?!
是嗎？
And when a Kaiju's powerful enough to get a number,
而且擁有編號的怪獸被打倒之後
I've heard they use its body as parts for a special weapon after they defeat it.
聽說會被用來做成特殊兵器的零件
It's possible that'll happen to you.
最壞的情況，你就會變成這樣
Kikoru, please! Please keep this our little secret!
琪歌露，拜託你，這件事一定要幫我保密
Save an old man's life!
救救我這個大叔啊
You're too close! Way too close!
你離我太近了
Please, please, please!
求求你…
Fine.
我知道了啦
You did save my life, so I'll keep quiet about it for now.
看在你救了我的份上，我就暫時保密
In exchange,
作為交換條件
if I find out that you're a Kaiju that's going to harm mankind,
要是我發現你是會危害人類的怪獸
I'll kill you.
我就會殺了你
Yeah.
嗯
If that happens, I'm counting on you!
到時候就拜託你了
Arms tight against your sides, wrists slack.
手臂夾緊，手腕放鬆
Let your instincts take over when you aim the reticle,
憑感覺掌握準星
and don't pull the trigger...
扳機不是要扣下
Squeeze it!
而是要壓緊
Squeeze!
壓緊
Reno Ichikawa, fire training exercise complete.
市川雷諾，射擊訓練結束
Time, 2:35.
時間是2分35秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 18%.
推測解放戰力為18%
Haruichi-kun, I've got a question!
陽一，我有問題想問你
I'm impressed. He's grown a lot in a very short time.
短時間就進步這麼多，真驚人啊
Reno set another personal best!
雷諾這小子又進步了
Come on!
看我的
I won't let him beat me!
我才不會輸給他
Iharu Furuhashi, 2:15.
古橋伊春，2分15秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 20%.
推測解放戰力為20%
Hell yeah!
好耶
I win!
我贏了
Don't get cocky, Reno.
雷諾，你可別太囂張
I won't.
我才沒有
Kikoru Shinomiya, 1:16.
四之宮琪歌露，1分16秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 55%.
推測解放戰力為55%
Play nice, kids.
你們好好相處嘛
Both of your scores combined are still worse than mine.
畢竟你們兩個加起來還輸我呢
Sheesh.
真是的
The more I train, the more she makes me realize just how average I am.
越訓練越發現自己有多平凡
You've got time to worry about people better than you?
陽一，你還有空顧慮前面的人嗎？
My combat power's as good as yours now.
我的戰力追上你了
I've got to worry about those above me and those below me, huh?
我被前後夾攻了是吧
I'll set a new best when it's my turn, Aoi.
我會刷新紀錄的，葵
Kafka Hibino, 6:39.
日比野卡夫卡，6分39秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 1%.
推測解放戰力為1%
Yes!
好耶
Did you see that, Kikoru?
琪歌露，看到沒？
I finally turned that zero into a one!
我終於從0變成1了
Stay away from me!
-你別過來 -怎樣？快誇獎我
Why are you acting so happy when you're 1% and I'm 55%?
為什麼你這個1%的 要來跟55%的我炫耀啊？
Kafka!
-卡夫卡 -是，保科副隊長
You're never gonna be a full officer at this rate.
再這樣下去，你無法成為正式隊員喔
You'll be fired in three months.
三個月後就會被開除了
WHAT?
（什麼？）
Old dude...
大叔啊
Okay, ten laps around the perimeter and we call it a day.
好，沿著外圈跑完十圈後 今天就可以解散了
What?
什麼？
You complained, so now it's fifteen.
有意見的話就跑15圈
Get going!
-快去 -瞭解
The new recruits have quite a few rivalries between them already, huh?
新人之間的競爭很激烈呢
Yeah.
是啊，在我看不到的地方
they're competing with each other and making each other better.
他們似乎也會互相切磋琢磨呢
I'm so tired!
累死了
We had to do laps at the end, too... The vice-captain is a monster.
最後竟然還要跑外圈，副隊長是魔鬼
Looks like you need to build up some more muscle, Reno.
雷諾，你的肌肉還練得不夠
No, yours aren't that much different than mine.
不，伊春你也差不多吧
Our fitness eval scores are always the same.
體能測驗也跟我不相上下
Are you serious? Look at these biceps!
你仔細看看我的肱二頭肌
They look like they're just for show to me.
中看不中用而已吧
Reno's more stubborn than I thought.
沒想到雷諾這麼好勝啊
Quit bickering over stupid stuff, kids.
這種小事有什麼好爭的
Behold the muscles of a hard-working grown-up!
看看我這身勞動過的成人肌肉，安靜點吧
Wow, you're getting some bulk...
哇，大叔你也滿結實…
BOUNCE
（炸出）
Aww, so close!
不行，太可惜了
You can't be in the Defense Force with a spare tire!
這是防衛隊員不該有的大肚腩
That's very rude, Iharu-kun.
沒禮貌耶，伊春
It'll happen to you too when you hit 28 or so!
你們這些傢伙 等過了28歲以後就知道了
I've actually lost a ton of weight!
我這樣已經瘦很多了
Forget the stomach.
別提肚子了
I challenge you all to arm wrestling!
我們來比腕力啊
Yer on!
-奉陪到底 -好啊
Okay, let me just set a towel down here...
那在這裡舖毛巾…
Huh. It's awful noisy tonight.
今天還真是熱鬧啊
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
We were just talking about how scrawny we all were.
我們都只是骨瘦如柴的男孩
Just what you'd expect from a former military officer.
不愧是前自衛官
What matters isn't your muscles!
重點不是肌肉…
You know, it's been a while since I've done anything like this.
總覺得好久沒有這種感覺了
I'll outdo you in training tomorrow!
明天演習時來較勁啊
You won't beat me!
我不會輸的
But did you expect any less?
想也知道是這個結果
That's right.
是啊
Excuse us!
抱歉，打擾了
It's fine.
沒關係，我也該出去了
Thank you!
謝謝
-We talked to her! -She's so cool.
-我們跟她講到話了 -她好帥氣喔
Are you feeling all better?
你身體沒事了嗎？
Yes. I'm fine now, thank you.
是的，託您的福，已經沒問題了
Wow...
真厲害
She's got good muscles, and just the right amount too.
她結實的肌肉恰到好處
But that's not enough to explain her combat power.
但這不足以解釋她的戰鬥力
What?
怎麼了？
I was wondering how you got those muscles...
抱歉，我在想您那身肌肉…
I mean, what kind of training you did.
不，我很好奇您是怎麼鍛鍊的
Stand next to me.
你過來我旁邊
I'll show you the basics.
我來教你基本動作
Here?
在這裡嗎？
So why'd you guys all decide to join up?
對了，你們為什麼想加入防衛隊？
If you want to ask other people, you should start by giving your own reasons.
問別人之前
For me, it's definitely Captain Ashiro.
我完全是為了亞白隊長
She saved me when I was in middle school, and I've always wanted to be like her!
自從我國中時被她拯救之後 我就一直很崇拜她
What about you guys?
你們咧？
Part of it's my family,
有一部分是家庭因素 但我的理由也跟你差不多
My goal is Captain Ashiro.
亞白隊長是我的目標
Same here.
我也一樣
That poster of Captain Ashiro was so cool.
亞白隊長的海報真的很帥氣
And she was so awesome in that documentary!
前陣子的紀錄片也有夠精彩
Mina's really inspired a lot of people, huh?
米娜的影響力這麼大啊
She's our generation's superhero.
畢竟她是我們這個世代的超級英雄
So what's your story, old dude?
那大叔你咧？
Well, I...
呃，我…
What?!
什麼？
Captain A-Ashiro is...
亞白隊長是…
your childhood friend?
你的青梅竹馬？
Y-Yeah.
嗯
And you both promised to join the Defense Force?
而且你們還約好要一起加入防衛隊
Like a "childhood promise" kinda thing?
就像「那天的約定」那樣嗎？
Well, I think I've had enough...
我差不多泡夠了…
Wait.
等等
Let's hear the rest of that story.
快把詳情告訴我們
Oh, well, she was born on a very sunny day...
呃，米娜出生那天的天氣很好…
She's always liked squid.
-她從小就愛吃魷魚絲 -真令人意外
She took care of the class pets in elementary school...
小學的時候，她擔任飼育股長…
Give us more.
再多說一點
And then... and then...
呃，然後…
That was a great bath.
泡澡真舒服
Did a serial killer come through here?
是發生連環凶殺案了嗎？
Oh, Kikorun.
琪歌露
They ended up talking so much they stayed in the bath too long.
聽說他們聊得太起勁，泡到頭暈了
They were talking about Captain Ashiro, they said.
好像是在聊亞白隊長的話題
Stupid boys.
男生真是愚蠢
I don't have a lot of time.
我沒時間了
I'll have to work twice as hard as everybody.
我得比別人加倍努力才行
Working hard, huh?
你真拼命啊
Vice-Captain Hoshina!
-保科副隊長！ -睡覺也是工作的一部分喔
I can't let myself get fired.
因為我不能被開除
For Captain Ashiro?
是為了亞白隊長嗎？
How did you know?!
你怎麼知道？
You were telling everyone in the bath, right?
你之前在澡堂裡說的啊
Assume every word you say in this dorm will be recorded.
你要記得，在這個宿舍裡 所有對話都會被監聽
Scary!
好恐怖！
I promised I'd fight by her side!
我跟她約好了，要與她並肩作戰
Oh, you know I could interpret that as saying
這樣聽起來好像是
you're going to steal my vice-captain spot.
你想搶走我這個副隊長的位子
I didn't mean it like that...
我不是這個意思
No.
不對
I do mean it. I'll do my best to make it happen.
我會朝著這個方向努力
Fine.
很好
You've got two more hours.
只能再兩個小時
Turn off the lights when you leave and lock the door.
離開房間時，記得關燈上鎖
I'm not letting you have my spot next to Captain Ashiro.
亞白隊長旁邊的位子，我不會讓給你的
-Thank you... -And...
-謝謝… -還有一件事
You shouldn't get too close to the rest of the officers.
隊員之間還是別混得太熟比較好
In this line of work, something could happen to any one of them at any time.
因為這份工作 什麼時候有人出事都不奇怪
A Kaiju?
怪獸？
This isn't a training exercise, is it?
這不是訓練吧？
See what I just said?
我話才剛說完而已
Let's go. It's time for your first mission.
走吧，你的第一個任務來了